nerc.ac.uk 2016-06-23

# NERC - Privacy and cookies

  * Home
  * About this site
  * Privacy & cookies

## Privacy policy

We collect information or data about you when you use this website.

This includes your computer's IP address and details about which web browser and device you are using (eg the version and screen size), and information on how you use this website, including the pages you visit, using analytics and cookies to help us improve the website.

This enables us to ensure this website works correctly for as many devices as possible, and we monitor the relative popularity of different parts of the site to ensure content is of interest and being accessed.

We cannot personally identify you with this information, unless you provide it yourself.

### Storing your data

We will store your data to ensure an adequate level of protection for your data protection rights and freedoms. This sometimes may involve the use of assured third party systems.

### Disclosing your information

We will not pass on your details to other providers, unless you give your consent for us to do so, and we will not share your information with any other organisations for marketing, market research or commercial purposes.

We may need to pass on your personal information if we have a legal obligation to do so.

### Processing your personal data

We handle personal data in compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998, and recognise the importance of the correct and lawful processing of personal data in maintaining confidence in our operations.

Further information can be found in our information notice.

## Cookies policy

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example:

  * enabling a service to recognise your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast.

You can use your web browser's settings to manage these small files yourself.

### Our use of cookies

We use analytics cookies provided by Google to monitor the smooth running of our site and to improve the service we offer, based on the usage and popularity of different content. More details on these cookies and how to manage them can be found on the [Google Technologies & Principles \- external link -](http://www.google.com/intl/en_gb/policies/technologies/types/ "external link") pages.

We also use our own cookies in order to comply with EU legislation on cookies and to allow selection of an alternative high-contrast colour scheme for users who have trouble reading our standard site (this is selectable from the accessibility page).

### How to control and delete cookies

We will not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.

However, if you wish to restrict or block the cookies which are set by our websites, or indeed any other website, you can do this through your browser settings. The Help function within your browser should tell you how.

Alternatively, you may wish to visit [AboutCookies.org \- external link -](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "external link") which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your machine as well as more general information about cookies.

Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of our website.

If you wish to view your cookie code, just click on a cookie to open it. You'll see a short string of text and numbers. The numbers are your identification card, which can only be seen by the server that gave you the cookie. For information on how to do this on the browser of your mobile phone, you will need to refer to your handset manual.

To opt-out of third parties' collection of data during your visit to our website, please refer to their websites for further information.

## Further information

If you have any queries about privacy or cookies, please contact:

**The Web Team**
